A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, M-R FA393
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Parker, Dorothy
  In 1960, Parker became the Foundation's first female officer in the Agricultural Sciences when she was appointed Assistant Director for Agricultural Sciences in the RF's New York Office. In 1963 she was promoted to Associate Director for Agricultural Sciences. Parker retired in 1970, but continued working as a consultant for the Rockefeller Foundation's Agricultural Sciences program for another decade.
  Parker's publications include Primer for Agricultural Libraries (1968), Library Report for the Indian Council on Agricultural Research (1969), and Guide for an Agricultural Library Survey for Developing Countries (1970).
  Dorothy I. Parker passed away in White Plains, New York, on July 30, 1999.
  India; Mexico
  - 1960 (Box 360)
  - 1961 (Box 361)
  - 1962 (Box 361)
  - 1963 January-February (Box 362)
  - 1963 March-April (Box 362)
  - 1963 May (Box 362)
  - 1963 June (Box 362)
  - 1963 July-September (Box 362)
  - 1963 October (Box 362)
  - 1963 November-December (Box 362)
  - 1964 (Box 362)
  - 1965 (Box 363)
  - 1966 (Box 363)
  - 1967 (Box 364)
  - 1968 (Box 364)
  - 1969 (Box 365)
- Parson, William
  - 1972-1973 (Box 365)
- Patten, Bradley M.
  - 1934-1935 (Box 365)
- Paul, J. Harland
  - 1944, 1946 (Box 365)
- Payne, George C.
  - 1944-1947 (Box 366)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 366)
  - 1951-1953 (Box 366)
- Pearce, Richard M.
  - Trip Schedule, 1916-1917, 1919-1921; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 18 pages (Reel M Pea 1, Frame 1, Box 367)
    18 pages, Trip Schedule and Medical Schools of Canada Progress Report
    Europe; East Asia; Public health; Medical education; South America; Canada
  - Index (Topical Reference), 1920-1921; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 6 pages (Reel M Pea 1, Frame 19, Box 367)
    Index (Topical References)
    indexes (reference sources); Public health; Medical education
  - Index (Reference by Staff Members and Others), 1920-1921; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 5 pages (Reel M Pea 1, Frame 25, Box 367)
    Index (References to Staff Members and Others)
    Public health; indexes (reference sources); Medical education
  - Index, 1920-1921; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills (Box 367)
    30 page index for years 1920-1921
    Medical education; Public health; indexes (reference sources)
  - 1920 November 15-1921 February 28, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 124 pages (Reel M Pea 1, Frame 60, Box 367)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on advancing medical science and advancing aid of medical education. The diary includes Memorandum "Relating to Chinese Pharmacopeia", various letters, table of Chinese Books, Medical education courses and an itinerary of 3 April 1921- 30 May 1921.
    Typhus fever; Nursing; Public health; Hygiene; Medical education; Bacteriology; Diaries; Peking. Union Medical College
  - 1921 October- November, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 10 pages (Box 367)
    Diary Hong Kong, Singapore, Bangkok, Hanoi and Shanghai. Brief 10 page diary that focuses on medical education, public health and hygiene.
    Hygiene; Asia; Public health; Diaries; Medical education
  - Exhibits, 1921; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 57 pages (Box 367)
    Exhibits in connection with Pearce's China Tour.
    Public health; Medical education; Hygiene; Asia
  - Addenda, 1921; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 13 pages (Box 367)
    Agenda to Accompany Richard M. Pearce's Notes on China Tour.
    Public health; Medical education; Hygiene; China; Asia
  - 1922 March 2-June 17, Peking. Union Medical College; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 132 pages (Box 367, Reel M Pea 1, Frame 186)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on surveying medical schools, teaching methods of medical education, creating medical science, distributing medical literature and laboratory supplies. The diary includes Richard M. Pearce Diary of China Tour 14 April- 17 June 1922.
    Nursing; Medical education; Hygiene; China; Diaries; Philippines; Public health; United States; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education
  - 1922, Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 4 pages (Reel M Pea 1, Frame 404, Box 367)
    A brief 4 page diary preparing for the tour of Brazil.
    Diaries; Hygiene; Medical education; Public health; United States
  - Brazil, 1922; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 101 pages (Box 367)
    Sope and Contents note
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on surveying medical schools, teaching methods of medical education, creating medical science and distributing medical literature and laboratory supplies. Pearce tours Brazil to survey local medical universities to assessing for reorganization. Pearce also attends various conferences.
    Medical education; Public health; United States; Brazil; Canada; Hygiene; Diaries
  - Exhibits, 1922; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 46 pages (Box 367)
    Exhibits in connection with the 1922 diary concerning medical education, coursework and public health.
    Hygiene; Public health; Medical education
  - European Trip, 1922 September 23- 1923 April 27; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 101 pages (Box 367)
    Pearce takes a trip to Europe to study the conditions in Medical Schools of central Europe. Pearce tours various laboratories, universities and hospitals. The diary includes the itinerary for the European trip and includes various lists of persons met.
    Belgium; Czechoslovakia; Austria; Germany; Hungary; France; Poland; Public health; Hygiene; Medical education; Switzerland; United States; Diaries
  - 1923, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 210 pages (Box 368, Reel M Pea 1, Frame 659)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on development of programs to assistance with medical education outside of the United States and China, emergency work in Europe and surveys of medical schools in Britain.
    Scotland; Diaries; Medical education; Netherlands; Nursing; Public health; Europe; France; Hygiene; Libraries; Belgium; Bulgaria; England; Wales; United States; Tropical medicine
  - 1923 Exhibits, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 54 pages (Box 368)
    Summary of conferences related to the 1923 diary.
    Nursing; Netherlands; Scotland; Public health; Hygiene; France; Medical education; Libraries; Bulgaria; Belgium; Europe; England; United States; Wales; Tropical medicine
  - 1924 January 2-September 29, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 42 pages (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 1)
    2 january- 29 September 1924: The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and of developing programs for the assistance of medical schools in countries other than the United States and China. The diary includes an itinerary for 23 February- 12 April 1924.
    16 February- 29 September 1924: The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and of developing programs for the assistance of medical schools in countries other than the United States and China. Pearce takes a trip to Europe and Near East to visit and survey medical education and hospitals abroad. The diary includes discussions of European programs.
    England; Egypt; Hygiene; France; Lebanon; Italy; Public health; Diaries; Medical education; United States; Turkey; Denmark
  - 1924 October 1-December 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 80 pages (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 150)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and of developing programs for the assistance of medical schools in countries other than the United States and China. Pearce takes a trip to Europe. Discussions of fellowships, literature programs and laboratory supply programs take place. The diary includes an itinerary for November 21- March 25, 1925.
    Germany; France; England; Egypt; Denmark; Belgium; Turkey; Diaries; Nursing; Public health; Lebanon; Medical education; Hygiene; Italy; Rockefeller Foundation. China Medical Board; Peking. Union Medical College
  - 1924 Exhibits, Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 45 pages (Box 368)
    Includes materials related to the 1924 diaries such as a trip to the Near East, European trips, conferences and interviews.
    Europe; Hygiene; Medical education; Middle East; Nursing; Public health; United States
  - 1925, Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 184 pages (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 275)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and cooperation with medical schools in the development of programs for improving their facilities. The diary includes investigations of the status of medical education programs, emergency assistance in Europe and aid in medical school development.
    Public health; Nursing; Medical education; Italy; Hygiene; France; Belgium; Diaries; Algeria
  - 1925 Exhibits, Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 12 pages (Box 368)
    Scope and Contents notes
    The 1925 exhibits focus on scholars, resident fellows and equipment allowances, conference plans.
    Public health; Medical education; Italy; France; Belgium; Algeria
  - Haiti and San Domingo, 1925; Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 19 pages (Box 368)
    The diary focuses on a trip to Haiti and San Domingo with training of men through Rockefeller Foundation fellowships, survey local medical schools, hospitals and nursing.
    Diaries; Nursing; Public health; Haiti; Medical education; Dominican Republic
  - 1926, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 172 pages (Box 368, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 472)
    The grants, visits and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on studying the present day needs in medical education and cooperation with medical schools in the development of programs for improving their facilities.
    Nursing; Public health; Medical education; Diaries; United States
  - 1926 Exhibits, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 10 pages (Box 368)
    The 1926 exhibits include Sao Proldem, Conferences and Interviews with Prince Mahidol Songkla.
    Public health; United States; Medical colleges; Medical education; Hospitals
  - 1927 January 3- May 31, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 149 pages (Reel M Pea 2, Frame 674, Box 368)
    Medical education; Medical colleges; United States; Public health; Diaries; Hospitals
  - 1927 June 3-December 30, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 140 pages (Box 369, Reel M Pea 2, Frame 826)
    Hospitals; Medical education; Medical colleges; Diaries; United States; Public health
  - 1927 Exhibits, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 7 pages (Box 369)
    The 1927 exhibits include a conference on Far Eastern matters was held on Monday March 28, 1927, RF medical education in Asia and public health.
    Nursing; Public health; Japan; Hygiene; Medical education; Korea; East Asia; China
  - 1928 January 6-May 28, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 135 pages (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 1, Box 369)
    The grants, visit and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on assistance in medical education, nursing education, miscellaneous activities in the medicine and biology. Pearce travels to Europe to survey medical education, assistance in improving research and teaching, and fellowship support.
    England; France; Hygiene; Belgium; Croatia; Diaries; Medical education; Nursing; Public health
  - 1928 May 29-December 31, Pearce, Richard Mills; Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; 122 pages (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 137, Box 369)
    The grants, visit and interviews with professionals in the field of medical education focus on assistance in medical education, nursing education, miscellaneous activities in the medicine and biology. The diary surveys medical education, assistance in improving research and teaching, and fellowship support.
    Diaries; Hygiene; Medical education; Nursing; Public health; United States
  - 1928 Exhibits, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Education; Pearce, Richard Mills; 2 pages (Box 369)
    Exhibits in connection with the 1928 diary concerning medical education, hygiene, nursing and public health.
    Nursing; Public health; United States; Diaries; England; France; Hygiene; Medical education; Belgium; Croatia
  - 1929, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Pearce, Richard Mills; 172 pages (Box 369, Reel M Pea 3, Frame 262)
    The Rockefeller Foundation Division of Medical Education reorganizes to become the Division of Medical Sciences. The mission changes from assisting countries with advancements in medical education to a policy in which research and the advancement of knowledge in medical sciences is considered the principle interest.
    Medical sciences; United States; Diaries
  - 1929 Exhibits, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Pearce, Richard Mills; 6 pages (Box 369)
    Exhibits in connection with the 1929 diary concerning medical sciences, hygiene and public health.
    Hygiene; Medical sciences; United States; Public health
  - 1930, Rockefeller Foundation. Division of Medical Sciences; Pearce, Richard Mills; 15 pages (Reel M Pea 3, Frame 442, Box 369)
    A brief diary of Rockefeller Foundation work in Medical Sciences before his death on February 16, 1930.
    Diaries; Public health; Medical sciences; United States; Hygiene
- Peck, Marshall
  - 1967-1969 (Box 370)
- Perry, Jesse P.
  - 1960-1961 (Box 370)
  - 1960 July-September (Box 370)
  - 1960 October-December (Box 370)
  - 1961 (Box 370)
  - 1962 January-May (Box 370)
  - 1962 May-June (Box 371)
  - 1962 July-September (Box 371)
  - 1962 October-December (Box 371)
  - 1963 January-May 1 (Box 371)
  - 1963 May-June (Box 371)
  - 1963 July-November 1 (Box 372)
  - 1963 November 4-December (Box 372)
  - 1964 January (Box 372)
  - 1964 February (Box 372)
  - 1964 March (Box 372)
  - 1964 April-May (Box 372)
  - 1964 June (Box 372)
  - 1964 July-August (Box 372)
  - 1964 September (Box 373)
  - 1964 October (Box 373)
  - 1964 November (Box 373)
  - 1964 December (Box 373)
  - 1965 January-June (Box 373)
  - 1965 March-April (Box 373)
  - 1965 May (Box 373)
  - 1965 June (Box 373)
  - 1965 July (Box 373)
  - 1965 August-September (Box 373)
  - 1965 October (Box 373)
  - 1965 November-December (Box 373)
  - 1966 January (Box 373)
  - 1966 February-April (Box 374)
  - 1966 May-June (Box 374)
  - 1966 July-August (Box 374)
  - 1966 September-October (Box 374)
  - 1966 November-December (Box 374)
  - 1967 January (Box 374)
  - 1967 February-May (Box 374)
  - 1967 June-August (Box 374)
  - 1967 September-October (Box 374)
  - 1967 November-December (Box 374)
  - 1968 January-February (Box 374)
  - 1968 March-May (Box 374)
  - 1968 June-September (Box 375)
  - 1968 October-December (Box 375)
  - 1969 January-February (Box 375)
  - 1969 March-April (Box 375)
  - 1969 May-July (Box 375)
  - 1969 August-December (Box 375)
  - 1970 (Box 375)
  - 1970 (Box 375)
  - 1971 January-August (Box 375)
  - 1971 September-December (Box 375)
  - 1972 January-April (Box 375)
  - 1972 May-December (Box 376)
  - 1973 (Box 376)
  - 1974 (Box 376)
- Peterson, Osler L.
  Poland; Hungary
  - 1945 (Box 376)
  - 1946-1947 (Box 376)
  - 1948 (Box 376)
  - 1949 (Box 376)
  - 1950 (Box 376)
  - 1951 (Box 376)
  - 1952 (Box 376)
  - 1953-1955 (Box 376)
  - 1956 January-September (Box 377)
  - 1956 October-December (Box 377)
  - 1957 January-March (Box 377)
  - 1957 April-July (Box 377)
  - 1957 August-December (Box 377)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 377)
  - 1958 May-December (Box 377)
  - 1959 (Box 377)
- Pino, John A.
  - 1965 July-1966 February (Box 378)
  - 1966 March-June (Box 378)
  - 1966 July-December (Box 378)
  - 1967 January-March (Box 378)
  - 1967 April-July (Box 378)
  - 1967 August-December (Box 378)
  - 1968 (Box 379)
  - 1969 (Box 379)
  - 1970 (Box 380)
  - 1971 (Box 380)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 380)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 381)
  - 1977-1980 (Box 381)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 382)
  - 1983 (Box 382)
  - Index (Box 382)
- Plank, Stephen J.
  - 1973-1975 (Box 382)
- Pomerat, Gerard R.
  Conditions Governing Access
  These diaries are temporarily unavailable for research.
  Hungary
  - 1946 March-May (Box 383)
  - 1946 June-August (Box 383)
  - 1946 September-December (Box 383)
  - 1947 January-April (Box 383)
  - 1947 May-July (Box 383)
  - 1947 August-December (Box 383)
  - 1948 January-April (Box 383)
  - 1948 May-September (Box 383)
  - 1948 October-December (Box 383)
  - 1949 January-April (Box 384)
  - 1949 May-June (Box 384)
  - 1949 July-December (Box 384)
  - 1950 January-May (Box 384)
  - 1950 June-September (Box 384)
  - 1950 October-December (Box 384)
  - 1951 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1951 May-August (Box 385)
  - 1951 September-December (Box 385)
  - 1952 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1952 April-June (Box 385)
  - 1952 July-December (Box 385)
  - 1953 January-April (Box 385)
  - 1953 April-June (Box 385)
  - 1953 July-December (Box 385)
  - 1954 January-April 9 (Box 386)
  - 1954 April 10-May 28 (Box 386)
  - 1954 May 31-December (Box 386)
  - 1955 January-April 29 (Box 386)
  - 1955 April 29-May (Box 386)
  - 1955 June-October 31 (Box 386)
  - 1955 October 31-December (Box 386)
  - 1956 January-May 6 (Box 387)
  - 1956 May 7-June (Box 387)
  - 1956 August-December (Box 387)
  - 1957 January-May 16 (Box 387)
  - 1957 May 17-August 2 (Box 387)
  - 1957 August 6-December (Box 387)
  - Hungary, 1956 (Box 387)
  - Hungary, 1957 (Box 387)
  - 1958 January-April (Box 388)
  - 1958 May (Box 388)
  - 1958 June (Box 388)
  - 1958 July-December (Box 388)
  - 1959 January-April (Box 388)
  - 1959 May (Box 388)
  - 1959 June-July (Box 388)
  - 1959 August-December (Box 388)
  - 1960 January-April (Box 389)
  - 1960 May (Box 389)
  - 1960 June-July (Box 389)
  - 1960 August-December (Box 389)
  - 1961 April-October (Box 389)
  - 1961 November-December (Box 389)
  - 1962 January-May (Box 390)
  - 1962 June-August (Box 390)
  - 1962 September-December (Box 390)
  - 1963 January-April (Box 390)
  - 1963 May-August (Box 390)
  - 1963 September-December (Box 390)
  - 1964 January-April (Box 390)
  - 1964 May-June (Box 390)
  - 1964 July-December (Box 390)
  - Far East (Duplicate), 1965 (Box 391)
  - 1965 January-May (Box 391)
  - 1965 July-December (Box 391)
  - 1966 January-June (Box 391)
  - 1966 August-December (Box 391)
  - 1967 (Box 391)
  - Diary Indexes, 1946-1954 (Box 391)
  - Diary Indexes, 1955-1967 (Box 391)
- Prager, June
  - Theatre Diary, 1980-1981 (Box 392)
- Prentice, Michael
  - 1973-1978 (Box 392)
- Read, Elsmer R.
  - 1941-1946 (Box 393)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 393)
- Read, Florence M.
  - 1920-1927 (Box 393)
- Rhind, Flora
  Flora M. Rhind rose from a secretarial position to principal officer at a time when few women held formal leadership roles in the Rockefeller Foundation (RF). Her career with three Rockefeller philanthropic organizations--the Rockefeller Foundation, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (LSRM), and General Education Board (GEB)--spanned thirty-eight years (1926-1964) and was characterized by a devotion to educational and equal opportunity causes.
  Rhind was born on April 28, 1904 in New York City. After graduating from high school in 1921, she began working as a secretary and taking evening classes at Hunter College. In 1926, Rhind joined the RF as secretary to vice-president and Division of Studies director Edwin Embree. She was transferred to the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial in 1928 to serve as secretary to Edmund E. Day, who took over the LSRM's social sciences work. When the LSRM was consolidated into the RF in 1929, Day became director for Social Sciences and Rhind returned to the RF.
  In 1937, Rhind was appointed the General Education Board's secretary for general education and assumed responsibility for its educational program. She quickly rose through the GEB's ranks: first, she became assistant director (a position she held from 1940-1947), and directed the GEB's fellowships program and its work in the U.S. South. She toured black and white southern colleges and universities, conferring with educational leaders about African American education. She then went on to serve as the GEB's secretary (1952-1961), vice-president (1961-1964) and, beginning in April 1960, the first woman trustee.
  Although she continued to work for the GEB, Rhind returned to the Rockefeller Foundation in 1948 to serve as corporate secretary, where she held essential legal, public relations, and record-keeping responsibilities. When the Foundation reentered the field of African American education in 1963 through its Equal Opportunity program, Rhind's GEB experience made her the RF's primary educational advisor and expert. In 1965, she was awarded an honorary Doctor of Law degree from Berea College in Kentucky in honor of her commitment to Southern educational and equal opportunity causes.
  On the occasion of her retirement in June 1964, John D. Rockefeller 3rd wrote to Rhind, "I personally will always think of you in relation to Negro education. In this area you have carried a heavy and important load, and will be gratefully remembered by the many you have come in contact with and by the many more who have benefitted by your understanding and wise counsel." President George Harrar, too, reflected on her remarkable career: Rhind "played a unique role in the history of the Rockefeller boards. No one of her present colleagues has served three Rockefeller philanthropic organizations. No other officer has known and worked with all of the chairmen and presidents of The Rockefeller Foundation since its beginning. Only one other woman has bridged the gap between a secretarial position and that of a principal officer of the Foundation."
  After her official retirement, Rhind took on a final project for the RF: Harrar asked her to lead a study of the RF archives, "and to plan how best they can be organized and maintained and to what extent... they should be opened to outsiders." The project's importance underscores the extent to which the Foundation valued her judgment and expertise, and solidified her significant legacy.
  Flora M. Rhind died on September 19, 1985, in Kennett Square, Pennsylvania. She was 81 years old.
  - 1948-1956 (Box 394)
- Richardson, Ralph W.